AMIR M. KARIMI

Software Engineer

@ amk9978@gmail.com

****+989024162768

lsfahan, Iran

amk9978

in amk9978

AMK

ABOUT ME

I am a back-end developer with hands-on experience of working on software projects for 4+ years experienced with 30+ projects mostly in JVM and in startups and also medium enterprises. I started my career when I entered the university. Fast adaption and taking advantage of patterns are two of my key strengths.

JOB EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Divar

Sep 2022 - Ongoing

◊ Tehran, Iran

- Back-end developer
- Divar is the leading application in the trade business of second-hand goods, job panels, and real-state markets in Iran with 50M++ users. A large enterprise with multiple technical teams working on a microservice project. I work on the maintenance and reliability of the website for showing posts to the users.

Golang Microservices Kubernetes Python

, ,

Software Engineer & Deputy team leader of Back-end team

Zamin

Jun 2021 - Jul 2022

- VP of back-end team of Balonet. A B2B multi-tenant business messaging company with 100,000+ users.
- Back-end developer of Balonet console from Jun 2021-Mar 2022
- · Active collaborator within a scrum team
- Automating the process of building a new white brand and also, designing and developing Java, PHP, and Python Balonet bot SDKs are some of my experiences here
- Download its Android client on the PlayStore

Kotlin Java Spring Spring-boot Akka actors MongoDb BDD Stress test

Co-founder & Software engineer

Scarlett

♥ Isfahan, Iran

- Co-founder of an entertainment industry startup, focused on movie recommendation and social networks, Although the team members changed several times, the startup survived. Currently, it needs an investor.
- Team creation and management, plus business concerns and state-of-the-art technologies are my achievements from this experience.

Python Django Recommender systems scikit-learn elasticsearch Docker CI

Software Engineer

Chandmahame Company

Mov 2019 - Aug 2020

- Developer of 3 android applications via Java/Kotlin See the last app on the Play store
- Back-end developer for application APIs
- Tech employment process designer and interviewer of php/Laravel and Android
- Covid 19 pandemic made me able to have a 30-hour workweek alongside my university courses.

Kotlin Java Android Laravel PHP Docker

EDUCATION

Computer engineering B.S

Area of study: Software engineering

Sep 2017-July 2021

♀ University of Isfahan

• Isfahan, Iran | Last 2 years GPA: b3.49 | GPA: 3.40

LANGUAGE

English

IELTS: 7.5 (R: 9, L:7.5, S: 7, W:6.5)



HONORS

8th place at MPM 2018

Among 50+ startup teams

Sharif university

Built and presented a rapid MVP with a business plan in 3 days.

Sharif Al Challenge 2019

Sharif university

UIAI Challenge 2018

₩ Nov 2018

♀ University of Isfahan

Top 1% of Universities entrance exam

Among 148,000+ applicants

∰ Jul 2017

♀ Iran

COURSES

LPIC-2 (Advanced System admin)

Offered by Gotoclass

∰ Aug 2020 - Sep 2020

See course info

Machine Learning in python

Offered by IBM

marc 2019 - May 2019

See course info

Advanced Recommender Systems

Offered by Politecnico di Milano

Mar 2021 - Apr 2021

See course info

In Scarlett startup, I took this course to use it in my work.

VOLUNTARILY

Council member of AI association

See Linkedin page, See Instagram page

May 2020 - July 2021

♀ University of Isfahan